If the employer does not examine the relocation possibilities before a dismissal,
there is no factual reason for the dismissal.
Notice that it is not that the employer must create a new job for the employee.
Thus, there is no right for an employee to be relocated if the employer is not able to do so.
Termination due to a lack of work takes place in accordance with a turnaround.
The turnaround is based on the employee's period of employment with the employer.
Employees with longer periods of employment have priority over workers with shorter periods of employment.
It is called "Last in the principle".
Note that there may be exceptions to your workplace.
With the new Employment Protection Act, all companies can exempt 3 people from the turnaround rules.
This means that employers with factual reasons may terminate 3 people
Without taking into account how long the employees have worked at the company.
This applies whether it is a small or large company.
But what happens if the employer is wrong, the employee may then claim damages
If employers terminate staff without factual reasons, ignores of the seniority rules
or does not comply with the rules on preferential rights for re -employment, the employee may claim the employer for damages.
The general damages in the event of an incorrect termination normally amount to approximately SEK 100,000
Thanks for watching
Like the video if it was useful.